Mamatraximov Umid

LinkedIn | GitHub

Frontend Developer | Tashkent Summary

+998 (94) 514 24 01 | umamatraximov@gmail.com

Frontend developer with 1.5+ years of experience. My main stack these days is Frontend (ReactJs & NextJs). During my career, I have completed various projects such as CRM platforms, sales sites, online learning platforms. I constantly learn new technologies and work more on myself.

Experience

Frontend Developer LIMSA

Februaryb 2024 - Current

- Used JavaScript and other technologies to help create the project's intricate partitioning.
- Development using React technologies for web-based versions of books.

Frontend Developer ITA

December 2022- January 2024

- Actively participated in a local Avtozom project, analyzed the project criteria, and created maintainable and scalable modules using technology that me and exceeded performance goals.
- I worked on a complex enterprise application using React and Redux or Context. I was responsible for creating reusable components, managing the state of the application, and integrating with the backend API

Projects

<u>Avtozoom</u> | During the development of the Auto Zoom website, I learned to work collaboratively. I participated in this project as a team leader and learned to use new technologies like Trello and Jira.

<u>Np Fabric</u> | While developing the Np Fabric website, I learned to work effectively with react-router dom. The useParams, useRef, and useLocation hooks greatly facilitated website navigation.

<u>Prime Build</u> | I used the AOS library, rich in various animations, in the development of the Prime Build web application. I also learned how to send a message to a telegram bot without a backend through a web application.

<u>Discover Invest</u> | I often used Bootstrap or SCSS technologies for my websites. However, for this particular website, I learned and applied Tailwind. I realized that Tailwind works much faster and more efficiently compared to Bootstrap and SCSS.

<u>Future Travel</u> | Developing the Future Travel website gave me the opportunity to get acquainted with the react-i18next and react-slick libraries. I learned how to change the page's language using i18next and add various carousel effects to the page using react-slick.

Skills

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs, Redux, RESTful API, Git, Trello, Jira

Education

Tashkent University of Information Technologies |Telecommunication

Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

Zako IT academy | Frontend Intership

January 2022 - September 2022

Languages Uzbek(Native), English(Intermediate).